DevOps Engineer

Profile

Experienced Elixir and DevOps Engineer with more than a decade doing both software development and operations. Current focus for the last 3 years has been Elixir. I seek to continue working in the Elixir space for the forseeable future.

Professional Experience

2021 - Present

Elixir SWE, Immersiva, Los Angeles (Remote), USA.

- Responsible for a full greenfield product rewrite of a Node.js based prototype game engine into AWS EC2 hosted Elixir, with a LiveView frontend that functions on multiple different platforms. The game engine state machine is a pure Elixir GenServer implementation.
- o Custom Auth0 authenticated Content Management System for content development including media uploads into Amazon S3.
- o Implemented CDN functionality utilizing Cloudfront for game assets.
- o Ensured LiveView functionality on multiple different hardware (Phone, PC) and browser (Chrome, Safari, Firefox) platforms.
- o Full OpenTelemetry instrumentation of state machine and LiveView platform.
- Full HTML5 Media player Client <-> Server communications in Javascript & LiveView.
- o Responsible for ensuring compatibility with other HTML based video players (Eg, Vimeo, Youtube, etc.).
- Built prototypes to test LiveView functionality on SmartTV platforms with TV-native applications.

2019 - Nov 2020

Elixir Engineer, SafeBoda, Kampala (Remote), Uganda.

- o Redesign 50 million call per day mobile application API from PHP to Elixir.
- o Migrated from Heroku to Terraform managed AWS infrastructure.
- Built NixOS & Ansible based deployments for frequent and safe Elixir deployments.
- Migrated AWS Aurora to regular RDS at a significant performance boost and cost savings.

2019 **DevOps Contractor**, Blast Technologies (Remote), Austrailia.

o Development of fully Puppet-managed Asterisk PBX.

- o Put some of that puppet work back into open source. [Puppet Asterisk module https://github.com/jowrjowr/puppet-asterisk] [Pupp
- 2018 DevOps Contractor, coder.com, Austin, Texas.
 - o Deployed GCP infrastructure for coder.com.
 - o Oversaw migration from CircleCI to Jenkins for self-hosted CI infrastruc-
- 2013-2018 **DevOps Contractor**, Upwork - Varied small & medium projects.
 - o Setup 50 node Chef managed cluster for a visual search engine concept, including a Ceph managed storage backend.
 - o Designed a Puppet-managed site deployment solution (~75 nodes) that deploys Wordpress sites as well as interfacing with associated registrar APIs to manage DNS. Hefty amount of Perl glue to accomplish this.
- Linux System Administrator, Rackspace, San Antonio, Texas. 2012-2013
 - o Was responsible for handling for RHEL, CentOS, and Debian support for Rackspace EMEA customers while simultaneously serving as an escalation point within my team for more complicated tasks.

Notable Personal Projects

o A conversion of a legacy PHP application that serves approximately a thousand users into a Python based REST API built upon Flask. This includes a core authentication migrationinto LDAP. This application interfaces with a large number of 3rd party external APIs. The purpose of this was to teach myself modern Python and support the IT infrastructure of an entity within a game I played. Ended up open sourcing it all once everything was decomissioned. [https://github.com/jowrjowr/triapi]

Education

2009 Bachelor of Science in Physics, University of Alaska, Fairbanks, US.

Technical Skills

Programming & Scripting Elixir, Python, Bash. Will only admit to PHP or Perl upon a binding blood oath that they are read only as they are unloved.

Languages

Linux. I know literally nothing of professionally managing Windows.

Operating Systems

AWS, Google Cloud, VMWare.

Cloud & Virtualization

Providers

Puppet, Ansible, Chef

Configuration Management

References

[Puppet Asterisk module https://github.com/jowrjowr/puppet-asterisk]

[https://github.com/jowrjowr/tri_api]

[https://gist.github.com/jowrjowr/56a36a3da9a039038b8504b73bfe2461]